<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://graygzou.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://graygzou.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-20T18:36:39+00:00</updated><id>https://graygzou.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Grégoire Boiron</title><subtitle>Grégoire Boiron's personal site. Host my portfolio, links to my projects and my own blog.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What I’ve learned during Advent Of Code 2019 :christmas_tree:</title><link href="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/challenges/2019/12/31/what-i-ve-learned-during-advent-of-code-2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I've learned during Advent Of Code 2019 :christmas_tree:" /><published>2019-12-31T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-31T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graygzou.github.io/blog/challenges/2019/12/31/what-i-ve-learned-during-advent-of-code-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/challenges/2019/12/31/what-i-ve-learned-during-advent-of-code-2019.html">&lt;p&gt;Like last year, I’ve decided to participate to the Advent Of Code 2019. 
And (like last year..), I also decided to tackle this event with a crazy challenge : Use Unreal Engine 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to check all my solutions for each year in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Graygzou/advent-of-code-2019&quot;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-unreal-4-&quot;&gt;Why Unreal 4 ?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a game programmer, you have to know how game engine works. 
Of course you don’t have to know several one. 
As long as you know one of them you should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally find interesting to compare them to know what they do best one compare to the other.
It’s also a good skill to have (knowing a few game engine). 
Since Unreal is used by some game development studios, it’s always good to add that kind of knowledge in my backpack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, I bought a couple of courses on that subject a while ago. 
So it was a good opportunity to make a good use of them. :wink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary-of-what-ive-learned&quot;&gt;Summary of what I’ve learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unreal does not deal with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.txt&lt;/code&gt; by default&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
You have to convert it first into a know format like a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.csv&lt;/code&gt;. 
Then you will have to import it as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.csv&lt;/code&gt; with a custom structure or not 
(depends if the csv is a made for a build-in feature of unreal)
If you do not follow those steps, Unreal will not display text file in the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code in Visual and launching Unreal to debug&lt;/strong&gt; 
I lost a lot of times doing the opposite. All due to crashed. 
I guess if you’re the guy that never encountered crashed when coding in C++, then this tips is useless for you.
So when I wrote my solutions in plain C++, I only had Visual Studio opened, and then launched the debugger to test it in unreal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read the documentation&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Sounds a bit cheesy but in this case it helps. 
I mean, when you use any third party software, you need to know how to use it right !
It’s the same for Unity, Cry-Engine, JMonkey, etc. Or any framework, libraries you want to use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard Library Class&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
This is the C++ class I’ve used the most when solving AoC puzzles. 
I find it useful because those correspond to standard C++ file without specific behavior.
I did not dig enough to be familiar with other C++ classes to make good use of them. 
To make a good usage of that class I had to make them all static and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BlueprintCallable&lt;/code&gt; (see next section).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actor Class&lt;/strong&gt;
In a couple of cases, the Standard Library Class was not enough. 
Because the previous class type can’t be use to spawn object, I had to use the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Actor Class&lt;/code&gt; instead. and visualize the result but those were one-off case.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UFUNCTION, UPROPERTY&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Of course, by using Unreal, I made a little use of some keywords. 
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UNFONCTION&lt;/code&gt; is one of them. This keyword is placed on top of C++ functions. 
It allows to specify special behavior for the described function. 
For example, adding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BlueprintCallable&lt;/code&gt; would make the function available in blueprint.
Same goes with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;UPROPERTY&lt;/code&gt; but for properties.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;favorite-puzzles&quot;&gt;Favorite puzzles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From all the puzzles I did in the 24 days, I really liked days 2, 6, 10. 
I found them interesting to solve. 
The problem was well explained, the examples were nicely presented and the background story attractive.
I also like them cause I ended-up with clever solutions for most of them. 
Two examples could be :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Day 2 part 2: I only the good old pencil/paper method to solve it with maths.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Day 10 part 1: the use of a simple dot product to solve the puzzle quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if I did not finish all the puzzles in the require time, I had a fun doing it.
Compare to last year, I did not tackle with the same spirit and the mind set which might explains a bit my slow progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to complete all of them in my spare time when I want to challenge myself !
See you next edition !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, you can find more on those links if you’re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Graygzou/advent-of-code-2019&quot;&gt;My Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://adventofcode.com/2019/&quot;&gt;Advent Of Code official website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.unrealengine.com/en-US/API&quot;&gt;Unreal official documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/blog&quot;&gt;Unreal official blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Like last year, I’ve decided to participate to the Advent Of Code 2019. And (like last year..), I also decided to tackle this event with a crazy challenge : Use Unreal Engine 4.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summary of my first participation of Advent Of Code</title><link href="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/challenges/2019/10/10/summary-of-my-first-participation-of-advent-of-code-2018.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summary of my first participation of Advent Of Code" /><published>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graygzou.github.io/blog/challenges/2019/10/10/summary-of-my-first-participation-of-advent-of-code-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/challenges/2019/10/10/summary-of-my-first-participation-of-advent-of-code-2018.html">&lt;p&gt;Little blog post (almost a year after my participation..) about my first participation to this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A collegue told me about this event and the blast he had when doing it with others co-workers.
Just by hearing the evelator pitch I was sold right away. (challenges, puzzles, computer science :heart:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was crazy enought to decided to do it in Lua. 
Compare to all my co-workers (4 of them) that choose C# or C++ which were the main languages we work most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to check all my solutions for each year in my [Github Repository].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-lua-&quot;&gt;Why Lua ?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might ask yourself why so much pain ?&lt;br /&gt;
Well, the answer is simple: I wanted learn something new. 
The point of my participation was not to solve fast puzzles but more like finding “beautiful algorithms” to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve already seen a bit of lua in a previous project (Raven) but I did not have the chance to really play with it. 
So I decided it was a good time to do so !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also heard some companies were using lua as a scripting language for their game / engine. 
Sp I guess, It’s always good to have more than one string to your bow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-counter-part&quot;&gt;The counter part&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Lua is great in term of scripting. But not so great to deal with some kind of problems. 
In fact, sometimes puzzles were easy to solve with a bit of abtraction. 
And, it’s not something really straight forward in lua.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) I’ve sometimes “re-invented the wheel”. 
Like coding sorting an array with a bubble sort which is a basic compute science exercise and is part of most array/vector libraries (contains at least a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sort()&lt;/code&gt; method). 
Or even apply a function to all element of an array. Those things require extra work compare to a language that already offers helpers functions to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overcome-lua-weaknesses&quot;&gt;Overcome Lua weaknesses&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Write a lot of unit test:&lt;br /&gt;
Since I split my work into many function without any classes, I had to make sure every function was doing what is was supposed to do.
To solve that problem I commit myself to write unit tests and make sure it pass before submitting something. 
Because, if you didn’t know, the more you submit to a challenge, the longer you will wait before being able to submit another answer.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add Comments everywhere:&lt;br /&gt;
I’m a person that love comments. I find myself writing some in order to organize my thinking when I do something. 
But in that case, it helps me even more with all the boiler plate code I needed to write.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t hesitate to create a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Utils&lt;/code&gt; functions: &lt;br /&gt;
I found myself writing some generic functions into &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Utils&lt;/code&gt; file because it was useful in more than one challenge.
I would not spent minutes / hours have to rewrite and test it again.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep thinking of other possible solutions:&lt;br /&gt;
Some problems were thouther than others. But some were computionally expensive. 
Meaning I had to rethink about my solution in order to be able to find the right solution. 
Also, some could contains patterns that could possibly avoid having to refactor and just find the solution right away (with a little bit of calculus for example)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;favorite-puzzles&quot;&gt;Favorite puzzles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself not finished the AoC 2018. 
Even if I see it as a bit of a failure, I’ve learned a lot and challenge myself once again.
I keep some good memories from this experience and will do the next edition for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;links&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Graygzou/advent-of-code-2018&quot;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://adventofcode.com/2018/&quot;&gt;advent of code&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lua.org/pil/contents.html&quot;&gt;lua documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Little blog post (almost a year after my participation..) about my first participation to this event.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tips and Tricks C++</title><link href="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/c++/2019/09/28/tips-and-tricks-ccp.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips and Tricks C++" /><published>2019-09-28T20:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-09-28T20:15:00+00:00</updated><id>https://graygzou.github.io/blog/c++/2019/09/28/tips-and-tricks-ccp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/c++/2019/09/28/tips-and-tricks-ccp.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;static--keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;  keyword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Values are stored at class level and not at instance level.
You have to initialize static variable outside the class in order to reserve the memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class C {
    static int i;
    static int j;
}

// Initialize the two static variables (with or without a value)
// Should be put at the top of the declaration (.cpp) file
int C::i = 1;
int C::j;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: If you declare a global &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; after static variables init, you can acceess it with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;::i&lt;/code&gt;.
Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;int i = 20
int C::i = 10;
int C::j = 5;

int g = C::j + ::i; // g = 25
int p = C::j + i;   // p = 15
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/!\ Static method can only use static declarations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;const-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; keyword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cannot be modified : attempt to do so directly is a compile-time error.
Modifing it indirectly (modifying const obj through ref or pointer to non const-type) results in undefined behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A const need to be defined when declared aka &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;const int x = 5; // without = 5 this will not compile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;volatile-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;volatile&lt;/code&gt; keyword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volatile is a hint to the implementation to avoid aggressive optimization involving the object because the value of the object might be changed by means undetectable by an implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mutable-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mutable&lt;/code&gt; keyword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Permits modification of the class member declared mutable even if the containing
object is declared const.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inline-keyword&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;inline&lt;/code&gt; keyword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All functions declared &lt;strong&gt;inside&lt;/strong&gt; the class/struct/union definition (.h) is an inline function like so :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class A
{
public:
    inline int test() // redundant use of inline
    {
        // this function is automatically inline
        // function body
    }
};

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline functions declaration can also be declared inside the .h but &lt;strong&gt;outside&lt;/strong&gt; the class definition.
But you need to also declare the signature of this function inside the class definition. An example of this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class A
{
public:
    int test(); // declare the function
};

inline int A::test() // use inline prefix
{
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;define&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#define&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arguments&quot;&gt;arguments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;constructors&quot;&gt;constructors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;class&quot;&gt;class&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create instances of a classe either&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;statically (Use class name as a type) &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MyClass myClass;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dynamically (Use operator new followed by the class name and optionally arguments between parentheses) &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MyClass myClass = new MyClass(arg1, arg2);&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;storage-class-specifiers&quot;&gt;Storage class specifiers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;auto: automatic storage duration.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;register: pareil que auto + hint compiler to place obj in processor’s register.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;static: static or thread storage duration and internal linkage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extern: same as static except external linkage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;thread_local: thread storage duration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mutage: does not affect storage duration or linkage. (const/votatile)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;possible-linkages&quot;&gt;Possible linkages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;no linkage&lt;/strong&gt; : Can be referred  only from the scope it is in. &lt;br /&gt;
Contains: basic property when declaring local variables + member functions not declared &lt;em&gt;extern&lt;/em&gt;. Just like typedefs, enumerations, and enumerators declared in the block scope.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;internal linkage&lt;/strong&gt;: Can be referred to from all scopes in the current translation unit.  &lt;br /&gt;
Contains: static variables, functions, or function templates. Non-volatile const variables (also constexpr) not declare &lt;em&gt;extern&lt;/em&gt;. All names in unnamed namespace.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;external linkage&lt;/strong&gt;: Can be referred to from the scopes in the other translation units. &lt;br /&gt;
Contains: variables not list above. Enumerations. Names of classes, members function, static data members. Names of all templates not listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;external&quot;&gt;external&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;extern&lt;/code&gt; is a keyword in C++ language that tells to the compiler that definition of a particular variable is exists elsewhere.
The counter part of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;extern&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; which tells the variables is only visible to that file/class (depending on where it is declared).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;void&quot;&gt;void&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pointers to void and functions returning type void (procedures in other languages) are permitted. Like so&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;void* ptr;          // void pointer
ptr = fct;          // Store a void function in this pointer
((void(*)())ptr)(); // Call the function pointed

void fct () {
  ...
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be used to mask the original pointer value :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; int n = 1;
 int* p1 = &amp;amp;n;
 void* pv = p1;
 int* p2 = static_cast&amp;lt;int*&amp;gt;(pv);
 std::cout &amp;lt;&amp;lt; *p2 &amp;lt;&amp;lt; '\n';            // prints 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tips&quot;&gt;Tips&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;string* a, b;&lt;/code&gt; : only &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; is a string pointer. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; is only a string.
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;string* a, *b;&lt;/code&gt; : both &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; are string pointers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">static keyword Values are stored at class level and not at instance level. You have to initialize static variable outside the class in order to reserve the memory. ``` class C { static int i; static int j; }</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting start with Jekyll</title><link href="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2019/07/28/getting-start-with-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting start with Jekyll" /><published>2019-07-28T00:26:29+00:00</published><updated>2019-07-28T00:26:29+00:00</updated><id>https://graygzou.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2019/07/28/getting-start-with-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://graygzou.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2019/07/28/getting-start-with-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;This is a draft post for now. Don’t mind about what is here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ref: https://jekyllrb.com/tutorials/using-jekyll-with-bundler/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you need to do :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ bundle install --path vendor/bundle
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if already installed run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ bundle update
or
$ bundle add jekyll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ bundle exec jekyll new --force --skip-bundle .
$ bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally run
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$ bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;%%%%%%%%
Ref: https://jekyllrb.com/docs/themes/#overriding-theme-defaults&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create own theme (overriding existing one)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First find the one you already using. To do that simply run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle show &amp;lt;theme name&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle show minima&lt;/code&gt; which is jekyll default theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give you all the file you need to override to create your theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:
The README.md is a really good source of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a draft post for now. Don’t mind about what is here.</summary></entry></feed>